the market let's just take a quick look
at that it's still down you'd have to
say there's no recovery that's come
through in the Nifty at the moment down
almost about 200 odd points but there
are plenty of stocks that are picking up
pace as well so look at something like a
coaching Shipyard up almost about 8%
right now a lot of PSU companies are
coming back LIC by the way that one is
above its IPO price of 904 so LC is
something that we're looking at this
morning 97 now on that stock and then
something like an intellect design arena
is also about 1 odd per. icsa Lombard
just get that stock up for you on board
the net earned premium this time around
for icsa Lombard has gone up 13 a half%
at little over 4,300 crores and that
stock is up almost about 4% reacting to
that the underwriting losses have
reduced as well about 4 odd per uh
coming in at 282 crores so in general
the you know the numbers were not too
bad and the stock is up and about if you
look at the premium growth as well the
gross premiums for icsa Lombard have
gone up almost about 4 OD per. so
volumes are picking up price action has
been good on that particular stock more
on that in Greater detail in a bit but
just a couple of more details all right
we'll get the management gopal
balachandran who's the CFO and chief
risk officer of icsl Lombard is with us
gopal happy New Year and thank you for
joining us on CNBC TV8 first if you can
tell us a little bit about the premium
growth that you're expecting you know
the net earn premium this time was not
bad at all 14% growth year on-ear
uh what can we expect as we move along
and in fi25 do you think there's a
chance that you could move above this
band of 13 to 15% in terms of net
premium growth so good morning Sonia and
seasons greetings to you and uh everyone
else to the channel and the viewers here
uh so I think when you look at uh growth
it has to be looked at in the context of
how you see the market momentum play out
uh as I have been kind of talking
through even in the past uh this Market
has always exhibited growth again if you
look at historical 15E track record the
market has grown at about 15% or
thereabout so even for the current 9
months the industry has grown at about
14% for the 9 Monon period and within
that I Lombard has grown at almost about
16.5% uh so this is something that we
have always maintained whenever we see
the market getting a bit sensible uh we
have always tried to have at least 100
to 200 basis point outperformance in
terms of overall growth numbers and
that's something that we are sticking to
even as we head into fi25 the momentum
across segments looks to be very very
positive whether you look at motor
health commercial lines activi seems to
be buzzing a lot and therefore as we
head even into fi25 as I said momentum
looks very very strong and given the
opportunity that the market present
presents we should continue to exhibit
let's say 100 to 200 basis point Alpha
over the market growth numbers the last
time you were a bit cautious in the
motor segment because of the
unsustainable underwriting and now
you're saying motor has improved can you
give us an outlook on what that segment
could look like so again from an Isis
alumar standpoint when you look at
across segments and I'll specifically
address the motor Point part that you
raised uh in general I think the theme
that we have largely advocated is
profitable growth as in to say that
wherever we see opportunities coming
back then obviously we have been able to
leverage on our various trends that we
have in terms of distribution service
and Technology last couple of years
motor as a segment at seen elevated
levels of competitive intensity play out
when you look at the first half numbers
which is available at a quarter's lag
for the overall Market the combined
ratio of that segment for the industry
as a whole has kind of improved by about
4 percentage points so there seems to be
some kind of improvement that a market
is starting to exhibit and in this
context is where when you look at it
from an icsl Lombard standpoint I think
we are seeing renewed growth momentum
opportunities for us uh in fact in the
last couple of years we have been
underperforming the market on motor as a
segment but if you look at for the month
of December the industry grew at roughly
about 9% or there about we grew at
almost close to about 11% so we actually
kind of again outperformed on motor as a
category and which is where I think as
we now look forward uh we believe that
the semblance that the market seems to
kind of exhibit on this segment uh we
believe there's a great opportunity for
us to ride the growth on motor as a
category even if you look at Motor
Vehicle sales across private car across
two wheeler and even commercial vehicles
largely maybe due to festiv demand rural
demand getting picked up in general I
think the sentiment of growth in volumes
also kind of is paying out to our
advantage and that's why as a category
we are very very positive and we rightly
poed to capture the opportunity for
growth in that
segment uh got that good morning Mr
balachandran it's always a pleasure
having you here prant this side uh so
you have a new leader Mr montri's come
on top is the CEO
MD uh what's what's the big kind of
message uh to you know down I mean what
are the what what's the uh one or two
things which he's very focused on and
what he'd like to
execute again good morning to you uh the
good part is sanjie has a part has been
a part of I Lombard so in that sense uh
he has been with the organization for
the last eight years he joined us in
2015 of course been with the IC group
for a very very long period of time uh
in terms of the point that you kind of
talked about as to what is it that we
would want to kind of focus on given
that he has now assume the position at
the top I think the thought process of
underwriting in terms of driving
profitable growth as a theme that pretty
much continues as an institution so
therefore even from sanjie standpoint we
will continue to kind of Drive
profitable growth as a theme across the
organization what we will obviously also
try to significantly focus on uh in so
far as sanjiv is concerned I think we
have created various pockets of uh
functional excellences we will obviously
want to kind of uh
kind of expand that and make sure that
we able to create a lot more
organizational EXC Excellence
initiatives and uh in that context is
where even from an industry standpoint
there's a lot of uh value pools that we
can kind of focus on and therefore in
the process Drive the theme that I spoke
about in terms of profitable growth uh
that we want to achieve all right hi
gopal good morning and thanks so much
for joining in can you give us a number
what kind of industry growth are you
factoring in point number one and point
number two the combin ratio I think it's
holding around that 103.6 you have been
telling us it'll come down to around
102% do you stick to that by 2025 and
also what's the tragedy post that so
Nigel again good morning to you uh so
again if you look at which is which is
what I just mentioned earlier if you
look at this industry over the last 15
years it has kind of grown at a
compounded rate of almost close to
between 15 and 16% and given the market
opportunity that it presents there is no
reason why this Market should not
continue to exhibit growth uh around
those levels uh in the range of 15 to
20% uh so as we kind of head into even
let's say fi25 that's what we would be
kind of penciling in depending on how we
see different segments play out as I
said in so far as is lomard is concerned
I think we would want to kind of
continue to maintain that Alpha of 100
to 200 basis point over market growth
numbers given the strengths that we have
in terms of distribution service and
technology so that's what we would kind
of Drive in so far as the Top Line
objective is concerned on your point on
combined ratios pretty much what we have
talked to the market is to try and get
to a combined ratio of 102% by end of
fi25 now that thought process continues
as we speak obviously this has to be
looked at in the context of where the
market is operating at so for example if
you look at the industry combined ratios
which is available at a lack of a
quarter industry command are operating
at about 112 this number if you have
looked at first half of last year that
number was about 116% so there seems to
be some kind of an improvement in the
overall industry combined and if the
industry Improv proves further from here
on then to that extent obviously we
would also kind of want to recalibrate
the 102% objective that we have set for
ourselves by end of fi25 but as of now
we're kind of sticking to the guidance
that we have talked about to get down to
102 by end of
fi25 okay all right got it you know The
Regulators formed a committee to detari
regulated business segments can you
confirm if this will bring the motor
third party deregulation under
discussion if yes would you support both
this and if it's done in your
understanding would it increase or
decrease the motor third party
premium so I think what if you look at
motor as a segment currently the way it
is structured is there are two
components of the risk that we underr
one is the damage to the vehicle which
gets kind of uh covered as a part of the
own damage premium and the other one is
the the segment that you refer to which
is the motor third party motor third
party at this point of time has been T
tariff which means there's a stipulated
price that kind of gets put out for
writing the risk at every year
there has as you rightly indicated there
has been a committee which has been set
up to look at a possible deregulation of
motor third party segment uh so
obviously we'll wait for the report of
the working group to play out but uh if
you look at in general the long-term
trajectory that even the regulator would
be want to looking at is to kind of
significantly uh free up the market and
get to market pricing so while
deregulation of third party could also
maybe result into let's say a reduction
in prices but at the same time what one
could also expect is a much better
pricing that could come through on the
own damage segment as well right so on
balance I think motor as a segment is
something that is likely to exhibit uh
better as I said growth momentum uh
including pricing as one of the factors
that one would kind of watch for the
other thing to look at in the context of
third party is the claim compensation is
basically out of court Awards now there
definitely what we are seeing is clearly
an increase in the average claims payout
that we have to to uh pay out to a
victim who is impacted by the third
party incident now that those
compensations are clearly seeing an
increase in the average claim sizes so
therefore any action on pricing has to
be looked at in the context of the
claims experience and as I said also
look at the overall pricing of the
entire motor portfolio so obviously
we'll wait for the report to come out
but I believe longterm again this is
very very structurally very very
positive right what effect does pricing
do will be a function of as I said the
loss experience as well Mr Bal Krishnan
we take that point thank you very much
for joining us and uh you know we hope
that next for the next quarter we'll see
you and Mr mantri both join us uh for
the for the quarterly interaction and
other interactions as well thank you
very much for taking out the time and
being with us here on CNBC TV8 deant har